<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meng Hui</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/</link><description>Recent content on Meng Hui</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Better Small Talk</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/better-small-talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/better-small-talk/</guid><description>Practice short interactions
Practice being emotional. Practice passage below
After climbing down from the china wall the travelers found themselves in a disagreeable country, full of bogs and marshes and covered with tall, rank grass. It was difficult to walk without falling into muddy holes, for the grass was so thick that it hid them from sight.
However, by carefully picking their way, they got safely along until they reached solid ground.</description></item><item><title>Managing Oneself</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/managing-oneself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/managing-oneself/</guid><description>WHAT ARE MY STRENGTHS? # Feedback analysis: note down a key decision and it&amp;rsquo;s expected outcome. Check back in 9-12 months to compare results with expectations.
Concentrate on your strengths Work on improving your strengths Discover where arrogance is causing ignorance and overcome it. e.g. lack of manners, interpersonal skills HOW DO I PERFORM? # Am I a reader or a listener? How do I learn? learn by writing learn by reading and listening learn by doing learn by hearing themselves talk Do I work well with people, or am I a loner?</description></item><item><title>Nonviolent Communication</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/nonviolent-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/nonviolent-communication/</guid><description>Not sure how this book can be applied on a practical basis. Interesting portion on self-compassion.
Components of NVC
observations - separate observation from evaluation feelings - separate feelings from thoughts, judgements needs - sense the feelings and needs in self and others. requests - through positive action language, state what we are requesting, rather that what we are not. ask for a reflection to check if the message was received correctly.</description></item></channel></rss>