<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Meng Hui</title><link>https://kohmh.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Meng Hui</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 23:01:03 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohmh.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/about/</guid><description>I am a Solutions Architect and have created solutions architecture for large tenders for hybrid environments and on premise environments. Although my title is so, I also take on other responsibilities depending on the situation. I have been involved as a Technical Manager, driving the product roadmap for ongoing product improvement and project delivery. I also perform periodic technology scans to evaluate suitability of technology adoption or integration for my organization.</description></item><item><title>Ideas</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/ideas/</guid><description>Useful ideas that have stood the test of time do not come by often. An idea is useful when it models reality as it is and provides ways to deal with how things are. Below in no particular order are ideas which changed how I thought about something. Where applicable, I will include the book I got the idea from and a brief description of why you might want to read it.</description></item><item><title>Software and Tech</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/software-and-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/software-and-tech/</guid><description>Software and technology changes rapidly. I have noted below what I hope will still be useful in years to come.
Writing Clean Code # Very generally,
use the package manager use dependency injection create systems/services/components along meaningful boundaries. Test them assemble them until you have your application use CI/CD Personal Security # Use a password manager. Don&amp;rsquo;t let breaches expose your password to other accounts. Use 2FA where important TLS Security # https://ssl-config.</description></item><item><title>Games</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/games/</guid><description>Growing up, I enjoyed playing games over other forms of entertainment. Mainly because I could play and experience the story as an interactive fiction. Recent games I enjoyed were The Witcher 3 and Divinity Original Sin 2.</description></item><item><title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-f_ck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-f_ck/</guid><description>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck - by Mark Manson # Date Read: 2023-05-05 # Notes # In short this book, is about choosing the right values and focusing on the process and not the outcome, about choosing pain over pleasure.
The desire for more positive experience is itself a negative experience. And, paradoxically, the acceptance of one’s negative experience is itself a positive experience.
Subtlety #1: Not giving a fuck does not mean being indifferent; it means being comfortable with being different.</description></item><item><title>Attached</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/attached/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/attached/</guid><description>Attached - by Amir Levine # Date Read: 2023-04-20 # Notes # 3 attachment styles: secure, anxious, avoidant
Anxious and Avoidant should avoid each other
Avoidant
Sends mixed signals values independence greatly devalues you uses distancing strategies emphasizes boundaries mistrustful uncompromising rules doesn&amp;rsquo;t make intentions clear difficulty talking about what&amp;rsquo;s going on Secure
Reliable and consistent makes decisions together communicates issues well can reach compromise not afraid of commitment or dependency doesn&amp;rsquo;t view relationship as hard work closeness creats further closeness introduces friends and family early naturally expresses feeling doesn&amp;rsquo;t play games Anxious</description></item><item><title>Nonviolent Communication</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/nonviolent-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/nonviolent-communication/</guid><description>Nonviolent Communication - by Marshall Rosenberg # Date Read: 2023-04-18 # Notes # Not sure how this book can be applied on a practical basis. Interesting portion on self-compassion.
Components of NVC
observations - separate observation from evaluation feelings - separate feelings from thoughts, judgements needs - sense the feelings and needs in self and others. requests - through positive action language, state what we are requesting, rather that what we are not.</description></item><item><title>Managing Oneself</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/managing-oneself/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/managing-oneself/</guid><description>Managing Oneself - by Peter Drucker # Date Read: 2023-04-03 # Notes # WHAT ARE MY STRENGTHS? # Feedback analysis: note down a key decision and it&amp;rsquo;s expected outcome. Check back in 9-12 months to compare results with expectations.
Concentrate on your strengths Work on improving your strengths Discover where arrogance is causing ignorance and overcome it. e.g. lack of manners, interpersonal skills HOW DO I PERFORM? # Am I a reader or a listener?</description></item><item><title>Better Small Talk</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/better-small-talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/better-small-talk/</guid><description>Better Small Talk - by Patrick King # Date Read: 2023-04-02 # Notes # Practice short interactions
Practice being emotional. Practice passage below
After climbing down from the china wall the travelers found themselves in a disagreeable country, full of bogs and marshes and covered with tall, rank grass. It was difficult to walk without falling into muddy holes, for the grass was so thick that it hid them from sight.</description></item><item><title>The Rookie's Guide to Options</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-rookies-guide-to-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-rookies-guide-to-options/</guid><description>The Rookie&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Options - by Mark Wolfinger # Date Read: 2020-07-12 # Notes # option price = intrinsic value (how much it is ITM) + time value (volatility &amp;amp; time to expiration)
When buying options, you profit only if stock closes above strike by option price.
(1) buy OTM option = time value (2) sell near expiration = intrinsic value (2) &amp;gt; (1) to profit from buying options equivalent positions: S = C -P</description></item><item><title>Unscripted</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/unscripted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/unscripted/</guid><description>Unscripted - by M.J. DeMarco # Date Read: 2020-07 # Notes # To have no one chasing me and for me to chase no one. It is about how much free time I can have NOW. Not later. Free time now is better than free time later.
Threats to Fuck This Event (FTE)
being too comfortable with status quo believing you are too good to do x. That x is something you will not do, no matter what.</description></item><item><title>We Learn Nothing</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/we-learn-nothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/we-learn-nothing/</guid><description>We Learn Nothing - by Tim Kreider # Date Read: 2019-11-20 # Notes # What if you had a brush with death but it did not change your life?
Difference between a bold romantic gesture and stalking? How it is perceived
Sometimes we become delusional beyond control - I was moved to unpleasant recognition by that photo of her face - gaunt and disheveled, deranged, exhausted, utterly broken and lost.</description></item><item><title>The Little Book That Builds Wealth</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-little-book-that-builds-wealth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-little-book-that-builds-wealth/</guid><description>The Little Book That Builds Wealth - by Pat Dorsey # Date Read: 2019-10-28 # Notes # 4 Kinds of Moats
intangible assets customer switching costs network effect cost advantages Mistaken moats
great products strong market share great execution great management Be aware of short term hype in these cases.
Businesses can&amp;rsquo;t change the circumstances they are in. Bet on the horse, not on the jockey.
Intangible Assets - brands, patents, regulatory licenses</description></item><item><title>The Risk of Discovery</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-risk-of-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-risk-of-discovery/</guid><description>The Risk of Discovery - by Paul Graham # Date Read: 2019-06-12 # A blog post at http://www.paulgraham.com/disc.html</description></item><item><title>Getting Everything You Can Out of All You've Got</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/getting-everything-you-can-out-of-all-youve-got/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/getting-everything-you-can-out-of-all-youve-got/</guid><description>Getting Everything You Can Out of All You&amp;rsquo;ve Got - by Jay Abraham # Date Read: 2019-03-07 # Notes # Book about email, internet marketing
Your business should create your own breakthroughs
know your strengths and weaknesses
thinks of everyone as clients, long term
offer a free trial
what is your unique selling proposition?
make them an offer they can&amp;rsquo;t refuse, provide guarantees, so your clients won&amp;rsquo;t make the wrong decision</description></item><item><title>The Bogleheads' Guide to Investing</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-bogleheads-guide-to-investing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-bogleheads-guide-to-investing/</guid><description>The Bogleheads&amp;rsquo; Guide to Investing - by Taylor Larimore # Date Read: 2019-02-09 # Notes # How investing is different from most of life. The following do not apply to investing
Don&amp;rsquo;t settle for average. Strive to be the best Listen to your gut. What you feel in you heart is usually right If you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do something, ask. Talk to an expert or hire one and let the expert handle it.</description></item><item><title>The Innovator's Dilemma</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-innovators-dilemma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-innovators-dilemma/</guid><description>The Innovator&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma - by Clayton Christensen # Date Read: 2019-01-29 # Notes # Sustaining vs Disruptive Technology
A company that expects 50% gross margin cannot compete in disruptive technology with unknown margins and a not analyzable market.
The processes and values (of the company, e.g. customer orientation, financial analysis) and ecosystem (suppliers, distributors) expects only premiumisation.
As such, companies won&amp;rsquo;t invest in disruptive tech until it is too late, when disruptive tech has reached performance parity with your tech, which has too much functionality by now.</description></item><item><title>Show Your Work</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/show-your-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/show-your-work/</guid><description>Show Your Work! - by Austin Kleon # Date Read: 2019-01-25 # Notes # You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a genius. Find a scenius. Be an amateur - a lifelong learner. Embrace the uncertain and unknown. Read obituaries. - What do you have to lose? Think process, not product Start out by scooping out the scraps. Journal your thoughts Share something small everyday What are you working on? &amp;ldquo;Post as though everyone who reads it has the power to fire you&amp;rdquo; Unsure?</description></item><item><title>The Art of Learning</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-art-of-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-art-of-learning/</guid><description>The Art of Learning - by Josh Waitzkin # Date Read: 2019-01-09 # Notes # Fame = emptiness
Unhindered by internal conflict - develop your technical skills in a way that fits your disposition
Confidence is critical for a great competitor, but overconfidence is brittle.
all situations can be handled as long as presence of mind is maintained.
respond to heartbreak with hard work - self motivation with a powerful resolve.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Possibility</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-art-of-possibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-art-of-possibility/</guid><description>The Art of Possibility - by Rosamund Stone Zander # Date Read: 2019-01-05 # Notes # It&amp;rsquo;s all Invented # Our senses bring us selective information about what is out there; second, the brain constructs its own simulation of the sensations; and only then do we have our first conscious experience of the situation
It&amp;rsquo;s all invented anyway, so we might as well invent a story or a framework of meaning that enhances our quality of life and the life of those around us</description></item><item><title>Willful Blindness</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/willful-blindness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/willful-blindness/</guid><description>Willful Blindness - by Margaret Heffernan # Date Read: 2019-01-01 # Notes # We like people similar to us. When trying to do something about it, become even more entrenched Love is blind. When it is spouse or family, you will tend to not see the problems Dangerous convictions - &amp;ldquo;No one likes to be told they&amp;rsquo;ve been doing something wrong all their lives!&amp;rdquo; Under too little sleep, you do not function properly Ostrich - choosing not to know.</description></item><item><title>Why We Sleep</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/why-we-sleep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/why-we-sleep/</guid><description>Why We Sleep - by Matthew Walker # Date Read: 2018-12-30 # Notes # How to sleep well # Stick to a sleep schedule (same for both weekdays and weekends) No exercise 3 hours before sleep (it raises your body temperature which persists after exercise, making it hard to sleep) Avoid caffeine and nicotine. (Coffee, Cola, Teas, chocolate) No alcoholic drinks before bed. (Affects REM sleep) Avoid large meals which might cause indigestion.</description></item><item><title>The Myths of Happiness</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-myths-of-happiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-myths-of-happiness/</guid><description>The Myths of Happiness - by Sonja Lyubomirsky # Date Read: 2018-12-27 # Notes # Hedonic adaptation - we get used to what is good, so it no longer provides us with any pleasure
In general, how to make better decisions (that are less clouded by your feeling unhappy)
note your intuitions and shelve them for a while, giving yourself time to think things through systematically seek the opinion of an outsider/take the perspective of an objective observer consider the opposite of what your intuition is weigh all options simultaneously, not one at a time.</description></item><item><title>The War of Art</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-war-of-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-war-of-art/</guid><description>The War of Art - by Steven Pressfield # Date Read: 2018-12-14 # Notes # Resistance - whatever that is stopping us from doing what we always wanted to do.
is internal, affects everybody fueled by fear stops us from becoming better takes the form of any preoccupation, e.g. sex, sugar, shopping, anything that provides immediate gratification anything that draws attention to oneself in a pain free easy way, e.</description></item><item><title>What Got You Here Won't Get You There</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/what-got-you-here-wont-get-you-there/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/what-got-you-here-wont-get-you-there/</guid><description>What Got You Here Won&amp;rsquo;t Get You There - by Steven Pressfield # Date Read: 2018-12-06 # Notes # Problems:
We think other people are confused. We are not the person that needs to change We go into denial We attack the other party Beliefs that made us successful make us unwilling to change
I have succeeded I can succeed I will succeed I choose to succeed These make us thing we have everything we need to succeed, like a superstition</description></item><item><title>Small Giants Companies That Choose to Be Great Instead of Big</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/small-giants-companies-that-choose-to-be-great-instead-of-big/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/small-giants-companies-that-choose-to-be-great-instead-of-big/</guid><description>Small Giants: Companies That Choose to Be Great Instead of Big - by Bo Burlingham # Date Read: 2018-11-29 # Notes # You have to choose some metric other than growth, &amp;hellip;, something you believe to be equally or more important Kept private as much as possible. Not practical in capex high business Is there a special meaningful context the business is in Close ties with employees and community is very important to these kinds of companies Succession and handover is tricky.</description></item><item><title>The Beggar King and the Secret of Happiness</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-beggar-king-and-the-secret-of-happiness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-beggar-king-and-the-secret-of-happiness/</guid><description>The Beggar King and the Secret of Happiness - by Joel Ben Izzy # Date Read: 2018-11-25 # Notes # Someone like you wastes time looking for answers, when you should be looking for questions.
&amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Ah,&amp;rsquo; said the old man. &amp;lsquo;That is where you&amp;rsquo;re wrong. For though I do not know which path leads out of these woods, I know a hundred paths that do not. Come, together we will find our way.</description></item><item><title>The Great Crash 1929</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-great-crash-1929/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/the-great-crash-1929/</guid><description>The Great Crash 1929 - by John Kenneth Galbraith # Date Read: 2018-11-17 # Notes # That we are having a major speculative splurge as this is written is obvious to anyone not captured by vacuous optimism. There is now far more money flowing into the stock markets than there is intelligence to guide it. There are many more mutual funds than there are financially acute, historically aware men and women to manage them.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to the Good Life</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/a-guide-to-the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/a-guide-to-the-good-life/</guid><description>A Guide to the Good Life - by William B. Irvine # Date Read: 2018-09-30 # Notes # Negative Visualization - contemplate the bad things that might happen. Lessens the impact when it happens. Remember not to take things for granted, to not get used to what I have now; that what I wanted before, I have now.
Internalize goals where you have control over the outcome.
Fatalism - to the past and present moment.</description></item><item><title>Antifragile</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/antifragile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/antifragile/</guid><description>Antifragile - by Nassim Nicholas Taleb # Date Read: 2018-09-19 # Notes # The sword of Damocles represents the side effects of power and success: you cannot rise and rule without facing this continuous danger - someone out there will be actively working to topple you. And like the sword, the danger will be silent, inexorable, and discontinuous. It will fall abruptly after long periods of quiet, perhaps at the very moment one has gotten used to it and forgotten about its existence.</description></item><item><title>Man's Search for Meaning</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/mans-search-for-meaning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/book-summaries/mans-search-for-meaning/</guid><description>Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning - by Viktor E. Frankl # Date Read: 2018-09-15 # Notes # Forces beyond your control can take away everything you possess except one thing, your freedom to choose how you will respond to the situation. You cannot control what happens to you in life, but you can always control what you will feel and do about what happens to you.
There is a scene in Arthur Miller&amp;rsquo;s play Incident at Vichy in which an upper middle class professional man appears before the Nazi authority that has occupied his town and shows his credentials: his university degrees, his letters of reference from prominent citizens, and so on.</description></item></channel></rss>