<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Meng Hui</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Meng Hui</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kohmh.com/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/about/</guid><description>I am a Solutions Architect and have created solutions architecture for large tenders for hybrid environments and on premise environments. I am certified Google Cloud Professional Cloud Architect, PSM I and PSPO I.
I also graduated from Carnegie Mellon University&amp;rsquo;s Master of Entertainment Technology program. I have created a Prison Yard Virtual Reality (VR) simulator, a Crime Scene Investigation VR simulator and a bus driving simulator. These projects have been featured on The Straits Times and ChannelNewsAsia.</description></item><item><title>Ideas</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/ideas/</guid><description>Good ideas are hard to come by. And when you come across a good idea, you wonder why you never thought in that way before. Below in no particular order are ideas which changed how I thought about something. Where applicable, I will include the book I got the idea from and a brief description of why you might want to read it.
Programming # Harold Abelson, Gerald Jay Sussman, Julie Sussman.</description></item><item><title>Software and Tech</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/software-and-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/software-and-tech/</guid><description>Software and technology changes rapidly. I have noted below what I hope will still be useful in years to come.
Writing Clean Code # Very generally,
use the package manager use dependency injection create systems/services/components along meaningful boundaries. Test them assemble them until you have your application use CI/CD Personal Security # Use a password manager. Don&amp;rsquo;t let breaches expose your password to other accounts. Use 2FA where important TLS Security # https://ssl-config.</description></item><item><title>Games</title><link>https://kohmh.com/docs/games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kohmh.com/docs/games/</guid><description>Growing up, I enjoyed playing games over other forms of entertainment. Mainly because I could play and experience the story as an interactive fiction. Recent games I enjoyed were The Witcher 3 and Divinity Original Sin 2.</description></item></channel></rss>